BRYAN FORD

2809 Airwood Dr. Nashville, TN 37214 · (423) 782-6236

BFORDCPA@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryanford1/ · https://github.com/FORDBA

ABOUT ME

Prior to starting at Nashville Software School, I spent six years working in corporate tax. During this time, I found myself becoming the go-to person in the department for leveraging technology to improve processes to provide quicker and more accurate numbers throughout multiple areas. This led me to become interested in the development side of the software I was using and, I have now found a new field that I believe utilizes my attention to detail and problem-solving abilities that I have developed during the course of my previous career.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL.

JUN 2020 - PRESENT

Intensive 6-month full-time software development program with a focus on team and individual projects to provide graduates with the skills needed to step into entry level positions.

- Created single page web applications using CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React, Python, and SQL
- Focused on building web applications with CRUD functionality
- Utilized JSON server and third-party API's for data.
- Developed wireframes and ERDs as part of the planning process

PROJECTS:

DRAGON SLAYER

Dragon Slayer is a web application built in React.js. This project was built to help connect guild members within an MMORPG to connect and share information beyond what is available in game. This includes setting up profiles for characters, commenting on bosses to add strategies and tips, and setting up events with an RSVP list. Link: https://github.com/FORDBA/front-end-capstone

SKILLS

- Use of Tax and Accounting Software including: Onesource Income Tax and Tax Provision, Oracle, Cognos Controller, Fixed Assets CS and Bloomberg Fixed Assets.
- Microsoft office product suite with a strong background in Excel
- Programming Languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Python, and SQL
- Process Improvement, Time Management, Teamwork

EXPERIENCE

LKQ CORPORATION

SENIOR TAX ACCOUNTANT

APR 2018 - JUN 2020

TAX ACCOUNTANT

MAY 2017 - APR 2018

- Worked with another tax senior to develop new system for state tax return work-papers that helped to reduce manual input into tax returns to provide a quicker and more accurate process.
- Worked on a major project with outside contractors to migrate tax fixed assets from Oracle to Bloomberg Fixed Assets, and set up new procedures for monthly fixed asset input. This project came in under budget.
- Prepared and reviewed several aspects of the tax return process including apportionment calculation, federal and state tax returns, and annual tax provisions.
- Researched tax issues, and prepared information to respond to state tax audits and notices.

CHANGE HEALTHCARE

TAX ACCOUNTANT

APR 2014 - MAY 2017

- Prepared quarterly and annual tax provision, tax returns and estimated tax payments.
- Utilized excel workpapers for several tax calculations and updated them for changes in laws and to increase efficiency.
- Assisted in preparing special projects such as R&D Credit and Transfer Pricing
- Maintained tax fixed assets.

EAST TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

TUITION SCHOLARSHIP

AUG 2012 - DEC 2013

• Tutored students in undergraduate accounting courses and assisted professor with grading and research.

EDUCATION

EAST TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY

MASTERS OF ACCOUNTANCY

DEC 2013

BACHELORS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION: DEGREE IN ACCOUNTING.

AUG 2012

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

JUL 2020 - PRESENT

CERTIFICATIONS

• Certified Public Accountant (Inactive) - License # 24400